# Paul Janson

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pauljanson002/

Github: https://github.com/Pauljanson002 Personal website: pauljanson002.github.io

Personal Email: pauljanson002@gmail.com Professional Email: paul.18@cse.mrt.ac.lk

Mobile: +94-776495354

#### Research Interests

My research interest lies in the conjunction of computer vision and deep learning. Particularly I am interested in the performance of deep learning based vision models in the 'wild'. I am focusing on removing the current limitations of deep learning based computer vision models such as their dependency on supervision and independent and identically distributed (iid) data. I conduct research in the combined areas of continual learning, zero-shot learning and domain generalization.

### EDUCATION

# University of Moratuwa

Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering- GPA: 3.90/4.2 (First class) Nov 2018 - Jun 2023

# Research Experience

### University of Moratuwa

Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

Oct 2022 - Present

Undergraduate Thesis - Advisor: Dr. Thanuja Ambegoda

o Generalizing Neural fields using Meta learning: Working on a meta learning based approach that helps to generalize neural fields to be able to reconstruct 3D object with single view. (view proposal)

# King Abdullah University of Science and Technology

Thuwal, Saudi Arabia

Research Intern - Advisor: Dr. Mohamed Elhoseiny

Jan 2022 - Nov 2022

- o Continual zero-shot learning with semantically guided generative random walks: Developed a method that combines creativity-based and semantically guided random walk-based losses in continual zero-shot learning. To avoid the usage of unseen class semantic information at training time.
- A simple baseline that questions the use of pre-trained models in continual learning: Developed a simple model based on the Nearest mean classifier that shows great performance on standard continual learning benchmarks questioning the usage of continual learning on simple benchmarks. (view paper)
- o Domain Aware continual zero-shot learning: Developed a continual zero-shot learning model with domain robustness using adversarial training. Tested its application on the classification of animals in the wild using camera trap images.

### ScholarX Mentorship Programme

Remote

Mentee

May 2021 - Nov 2021

• Vision Transformers for continual learning: Performed an independent study to use vision transformer architecture in continual learning. Developed a dynamically expanding architecture with compact transformer modules (view) (slides)

# **PUBLICATIONS**

• A simple baseline that questions the use of pre-trained models in continual learning: Accepted at NeurIPS 2022 Workshop on Distribution Shifts (view) Paul Janson, Wenxuan Zhang, Rahaf Aljundi, Mohamed Elhoseiny

• Continual zero-shot learning through semantically guided generative random walk:

Wenxuan Zhang, Paul Janson Divyansh Jha, Kai Yi, Ivan Skorodov, Mohamed Elhoseiny

• Domain aware continual zero-shot learning:

In review

Kai Yi, Paul Janson, Mohamed Elhoseiny

#### Teaching experience

### University of Moratuwa

Teaching Assistant

Moratuwa, Sri Lanka Aug 2022 - Present

• Theory of Computing: Worked in grading assignments and exams of undergraduate students

### Professional Experience

Yarl IT Hub

Jaffna, Sri Lanka

Intern

Feb 2018 - Oct 2018

• Aki E learning platform: Worked in content creation and website administration

### Relevant Courseworks

• Linear Algebra: A+

• Applied Statistics: A+

• Calculus: A

• Differential equations and applications: A+

• Intelligent Systems (AI): A+

• Research and report writing: A+

### SKILLS AND STANDARDIZED TESTS

• Programming Languages: Python, Javascript, Java

• Deep/Machine learning tools: Pytorch, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Numpy

• TOEFL iBT: 106/120

• General computing: UNIX, SLURM

• Experiment tracking: WandB

### SCHOLARSHIPS AND AWARDS

• Appeared in Dean's honors list for 5 semesters : 2018-2022

• Mahapola Merit Scholarship for Undergraduate education: 2018-2022

• Bank of Ceylon Nanajaya Scholarship for Undergraduate education: 2018-2022

• POH Scholarship by Zagro Asia Limited, Singapore for Undergraduate education: 2018-2022

• Dialog Merit Scholarship for Undergraduate education: 2018-2022

• Governors Award for best performance in GCE A/L (3rd in the country): 2017

### Volunteering and Professional Service

• Student representative for CSE department: 2019-2020

• Volunteer translator for open.uom.lk: 2022

• Volunteer at Yarl IT hub non profit organization: 2018-2022